# **Abbas Si Ahmed**

Southington, CT 06489

Phone: (860) 597 0040 - <u>Abbasiahmed1005@gmail.com</u>

## Professional Summary\_

Detailed oriented IT Professional with 10 years of experience in software testing industry with strong experience in automation. Excellent communication and problem solving skills. Good experience working in an agile environment. Solid experience working with onshore and offshore teams. Act with integrity and provide honest and realistic opinion. I always seek diverse perspective and fresh alternatives with respect and leadership. Great team player, and put time an effort to help others. Goal oriented with strong track record of achieving results. Good understanding of AWS Cloud, CICD, and AI technologies.

### Skills \_\_\_\_\_

- Agile Methodology
- Jira
- Jenkins
- GitHub
- Git

- Java
- HTML
- CSSJavaScript
- Selenium
- Ruby on rails
- Watir
- Gherkin
- Postman
- API Testing
- SoapUl

## **Work Experience**

01/2019 to 09/2024

### **IT QA Technical Manager - Automation Engineer**

### Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Co - Springfield, MA

- Created Gherkin scenarios from business requirements and acceptance criteria
- Developed automation test scripts for the application under test using BDD Framework
- Performed PR and code reviews and provided feedback and suggestions
- Responsible on regression test suite execution, analysis and reporting
- Responsible on regression test suite maintenance and updates
- Responsible on automation backlog refinement and prioritization
- Lead and tracked automation efforts within the automation team, and assigned work to the right team members
- Provided quarterly automation statistics and reporting to management
- Participated in all Agile ceremonies (PI Planning, Product Refinement, Sprint planning, and Retrospectives)
- Provided training to new and existing resources (Automation Framework, Gherkin, GitHub, Git, Jenkins, and Jira)
- Created training material in different format, digital and live presentation
- Worked as a Jenkins Admin including Jenkins installation and configuration, Jenkins access
- Involved in CICD pipeline creation and test orchestration in Jenkins
- Provided automation support, direction, and automation strategy

#### 07/2018 to 12/2018

### Senior System Engineer I

### Geico - Chevy Chase, MD

- Worked on non-functional requirement gathering by working closely with the business analysts, developers, and functional testing teams
- · Developed performance test strategies, and test plans
- LoadRunner script development, script enhancement, and validation
- Worked very closely with the SMEs to determine test data and data dependencies needed for the load test
- Responsible for Load test scenario definition, configuration and load test distribution
- Responsible on Performance test Execution, Analysis and Reporting

#### 05/2014 to 06/2018

### **System Engineer I**

### First Citizen Bank - Raleigh, NC

- Involved in test environment creation and configuration
- Performed Data staging, and testing environment readiness
- Non-functional requirement gathering by working closely with the business analysts, developers, and functional testing teams
  - LoadRunner script development, script enhancement, and validation
- Responsible for Load test scenario definition, configuration and load test distribution
  - Performance test Execution, Analysis and Reporting using LoadRunner
  - Performed Soap and Rest Web services testing using Ready API
  - Designed and executed web services load testing using Ready API

#### 05/2013 to 04/2014

### **Technical Helpdesk Associate**

### Xerox Consultant Company, Inc. Cheshire, CT - Umass Memorial Medical Center

 Provided first-level contact and problem resolution for all users with hardware, software and application problems

#### 08/2012 to 12/2012

### Help Desk, Networking Technician

### Insurity INC., Hartford, C

- Worked on Operating systems installation and configuration.
- Worked on Routine network problems troubleshooting, VPN, and remote desktop

### Education

#### December 2012

### **Bachelor of Science in Networking Technologies**

Central Connecticut State University, New Britain, CT

### **Professional Development**

- Full-Stack Web Developer In progress
- Scaled Agile, Leading Safe Certification
- Scrum Master and Product Owner
- AWS Technical Essentials